# **Ewaldo Simon Hiras**

## Digital Forensic Investigator

Bekasi, Jawa Barat

□ aldo@aldosimon.com

in linkedin.com/in/aldosimon/

aldosimon.com

## **Summary**

Extensive experience in law enforcement and investigation field, with 7+ years focusing in digital forensic. My employment background as an investigator requires me to be detail-oriented and thorough.

I have a huge interest in information security related topics, and hold a masters degree in digital forensics with thesis focusing in metasploit exploitation from a forensic view.

## Work experience

## **Digital Forensic Investigator**

2013 - current

#### Directorate General of Taxes

- Digital forensic team supervisor.
- Digital forensic investigator in several high profile tax investigation.
- Conduct forensic acquisition, analysis and presentation of digital evidence on various tax investigations. Using various computer and mobile forensic tools, mainly focusing in e-discovery.
- Trainer on several digital forensic training held by Directorate General of Tax throughout Indonesia.

Investigator 2007 - 2012

#### Capital Market Supervisory Agency

• Document examination, on site examination, witness inquiries, and reporting. Focusing in Capital Market crime investigation mainly regarding stock transaction and brokerage.

#### Education

## Master of Science in Digital Investigation an Forensic Computer

2016 - 2017

#### University College Dublin

First class-honour degree in computer forensic and information security masters degree. My thesis focuses on Metasploit attack from digital forensic point of view.

#### **Bachelor on Accountancy**

2008 - 2010

#### Universitas Indonesia

Accounting degree with thesis focusing in stock recommendation and returns.

#### **Diploma Accounting**

2004 - 2007

Sekolah Tinggi Akuntansi Negara

#### **Achievements**

#### Founder

#### digitalinvestigation.id

Community website focusing on newest news about cybersecurity, computer forensic and tech in general

#### **Panelist**

#### Indonesia Security Summit 2020

Panelist on Indonesia Security Summit 2020 on the topic "Digital Forensic Readiness"

#### **Panelist**

#### Indonesia Security Summit 2018

Panelist on Indonesia Security Summit 2018 on the topic "How IoT changes the face of cybersecurity"

#### Contributor

#### Cyber Defence Community eMagazine

Author on article titled "The Fault in our Shell", A summary on findings from running telnet/ssh honeypot.

#### Awardee of Indonesia Endowment Fund for Education Scholarship

#### Indonesia Endowment Fund for Education

Awarded a full scholarship on Msc. in Digital Investigation and Forensic Computing.

#### **Tutor**

#### 121 digital.ie

121 Digital provides free information technology training for adults. I tutored one of the learners in 121 Digital program in Dublin, on various information technology related matter.

## **Skills**

#### **Computer Forensic**

5+ years of experience in computer forensic procedures. Adept in various e-discovery/ digital forensic tools (FTK, encase).

I've also used cuckoo sandbox and volatility extensively while working on metasploit attack research for my thesis.

Autopsy/sleuthkit trainer in several class in Ministry of Finance and Directorate General of Taxes forensic training.

#### Mobile Forensic

5+ years of experience using oxygen forensic and cellebrite. I am also certified as an oxygen forensic examiner.

## Cybersecurity

held CCNA cyberops, very enthutiastic about the field esp. blueteaming, write tutorials and articles on various blueteam topics (e.g. sysmon, velociraptor, cowrie etc)

## PHP/python

I have used PHP and python to assist my work.

## Certification

## Access Data Certified Investigator

2020

AccessData

## **CCNA Network Associate Cyberops**

2019

Cisco

## Oxygen Forensic Certified Examiner

2016

Oxygen Forensics

## **Computer Hacking Forensic Investigator**

2016

EC-Council

Created with 🔽 VisualCV